Elkin Gutierrez

Data Scientist

(+57) 305 8751 268



@



Bogotá, Colombia

Economist with experience in data mining, business intelligence, research and math problem solving coaching. Interested in working on business intelligence, statistics, web scrapping and database building. Knowledge and skills include marketing in social media, natural language processing, API's usage, math, machine learning, pattern detection. Creative and flexible mindset suited for numerical analysis.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SUMA WEALTH INCORPORATED

Suma Wealth is a fintech. I came at an early stage of the company with a 4,000-person audience; currently, we have more than 600,000. I have built the data flow of all the social media platforms, one app, and an academy into periodic reports for other parts of the company, such as development, creative team, marketing, and management, I designed financial tools for the website and the app and had colaboration from two interns. Suma has used technologies like curios for NFTs, Heroku, AWS, and WordPress for development and data storage and has done collaborations, events, and marketing campaigns for big companies such as Turbotax, Chase, Wells Fargo, Verizon, Fidelity, and Stockpile

DIGITAL ROCKET/ANALYTICS

Digital Marketing analysis for various Colombian Pymes doing their jump into internet due to the pandemic. Building dashboards for some clients (Renauld, E2050). Data flow automation inside the company. Process automation (billing, inventory) and helped Digital Rocket with growth planning from 7 to 30 employees

ASYLUM MARKETING

Integrate performance data sourced from cross-platform media in an organized and concise manner. Extract valuable information from raw data. Provide understandable recommendations to stakeholders, both internal and external. Visualize data in dashboards.

Communicate concise data points, trends, and measurement strategies to a wide audience, from high-end clients to internal teams in Spanish and English. Ensuring analytical / GTM tags are properly crawled across multiple domains with flawless quality control.

ACHIEVEMENTS: Manage the data of the digital campaigns for more than 6 companies with large purchases: Motorola USA and Latam, Microsoft USA, Zebra, Latam Airlines, HP, Wacom Latam, Cisco among others.

WPP- GroupM (Warner Brothers Latam)

Reports of social media campaigns for the regional planning of Warner Brothers based on USA and the local planning's of central America, Brazil, Colombia, Argentina and Mexico. Increassing KPIs of trailer blasts and movie releases through pattern recognition. Explaining data Patterns and advice implementation. Data mining and algorithm development for automation, training on statistics and programming basics.

MITU INCORPORATED

Statistical analysis to optimize influencers recruiting. App optimization for a platform designed to make deals with influencers. Payout algorithm design based on social media fan page stats. Competitive analysis of social media campaigns done by Mitu for companies as Paramount, Disney, Hulu and Politic campaigns. Statistical analysis and scrapping on the market and social media to start a shop for we are Mitu.

COLOMBIAN MATHEMATICAL OLYMPIAD

Training the top high school level Colombian students in order to compete at international math contests. Member of the academic and selection committee and book's writing on LaTeX. Accomplishments: leader of the Colombian Delegation for the rioplatense mathematical olympiad, bronze and silver medal achieved.

NATIONAL PLANNING DEPARTMENT

Collection, cleaning and data base building of national spending on education from: Government Institutions, organizations, public companies, local entities and national surveys. From 1986 to 2015. Done at many levels: assignation, actual spent and others. Exploration of final data base.

DATA ANALYST

Nov 2020 - Present

DATA ANALYTICS MANAGER

Dec 2019 - Oct 2019

DATA ANALYTICS MANAGER

Mar 2019 - Sep 2019

SENIOR DATA ANALYST

Oct 2017 - Dec 2018

INSIGHTS AND RESEARCH ANALYST

Feb 2016 – Aug 2017

MATHEMATICS INSTRUCTOR

Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

INTERN

Jan 2014 - Jun 2014

EDUCATION

LOS ANDES UNIVERSITY

LOS ANDES UNIVERSITY

SERGIO ARBOLEDA UNIVERSITY

MSC IN ECONOMICS

Jan 2015 - Present

ECONOMIST

Jan 2009 - Jun 2014

MATH STUDIES

Jan 2005 – Jan 2009

AFFILIATIONS Y DISTINCTIONS

BRONZE MEDAL

5th place - 2007

NINTH PLACE

2013

SCHOLARSHIP

2009-2014

COLOMBIAN TEAM

Participation - 2007

OLIMPIADA COLOMBIANA DE

MATEMATICAS

BOLSA MILLONARIA – COLOMBIAN

STOCK EXCHANGE

UNIVERSIDAD DE LOS ANDES

AMERICAN REGIONS

MATHEMATICS LEAGUE

PROGRAMMING

R

SQL

Python

HTML

Stata

Office